<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jukelyn</title>
    <link>http://jukelyn.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jukelyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jukelyn.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup Nginx Proxy Manager Using Portainer (Docker) </title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/npm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/npm/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is Nginx Proxy Manager? Link to heading Nginx Proxy Manager (NPM) is a web-based, easy-to-use tool that simplifies the management of Nginx reverse proxies. It allows users to manage their reverse proxies, SSL certificates, and forwarding rules with a graphical user interface (GUI), making it much easier for beginners or non-experts to set up and manage web servers. Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of what Nginx Proxy Manager offers:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSL/TLS Chain of Trust</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/tls/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is TLS/SSL? Link to heading TLS (Transport Layer Security) and SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) are cryptographic protocols designed to provide secure communication over a network. TLS was developed by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) in 1999 to be an upgrade/replacement for SSL which is was developed by Netscape in 1994.&#xA;Why should anybody care? Link to heading Now that you know what TLS and SSL are, why should we care?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup Vaultwarden For Self Hosted Password Managing</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/vw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/vw/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is vaultwarden? Link to heading From the source repo1, vaultwarden is an alternative implementation of the Bitwarden server API written in Rust and compatible with upstream Bitwarden clients, perfect for self-hosted deployment where running the official resource-heavy service might not be ideal.&#xA;Why vaultwarden? Link to heading Here are some of the key reasons why I am choosing to use vaultwarden:&#xA;Open Source: Vaultwarden is fully open-source, which means its code is freely available for review and modification by anyone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup Nginx As A Webserver Using Portainer (Docker)</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/nginx/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is nginx? Link to heading Nginx (pronounced &amp;ldquo;engine X&amp;rdquo;) is an open-source web server software known for its high performance, stability, and low resource usage. It serves static content, acts as a reverse proxy and load balancer, and can cache HTTP responses to improve speed and efficiency. Its simple configuration and ability to handle many simultaneous connections make it ideal for high-traffic websites. Nginx is widely used due to its flexibility and robust feature set, with both open-source and enterprise versions available.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup Traefik For Reverse Proxying Using Portainer (Docker) </title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/traefik/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is traefik? Link to heading Traefik is an open-source edge router and reverse proxy that manages and routes traffic to services dynamically. It integrates with technologies like Docker and Kubernetes, automatically detects changes, supports multiple protocols (HTTP, HTTPS, TCP, WebSocket), and includes features like automatic SSL/TLS certificates from Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt (sometimes a pain in the ass). Traefik also offers middlewares for added functionalities and extensive observability through metrics and logs, making it ideal for scalable, high-traffic microservices environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All About SSH Keys</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/ssh-keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/ssh-keys/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is SSH? Link to heading SSH, or Secure Shell, is a cryptographic network protocol used for secure communication between two computers over an unsecured network. It provides a secure channel over an insecure network by encrypting the data transmitted between the client and the server.&#xA;SSH keys offer a more secure and convenient way to authenticate to remote servers compared to traditional password-based authentication. They are widely used in various scenarios, including server administration, file transfers, and remote command execution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, glad to see you here. My name is Mehraz, but I mostly go by my screen name, Jukelyn (hence the domain name). I&amp;rsquo;m an aspiring server admin who is currently working in an IT support tech position at the college that I am attending. I&amp;rsquo;m studying math and computer science at NC State University and hope to work towards a master&amp;rsquo;s in data science as well! In my free time, I love making new projects to further refine my skills as a developer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for your interest in getting in touch with me. Please feel free to reach out using any of the methods listed below. I look forward to hearing from you!&#xA;For general inquiries my email is a.mehraz.cs@gmail.com&#xA;Social Media: Link to heading Discord: Jukelyn LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mehraza Github: https://github.com/Jukelyn YouTube: https://www.youtube.com/@jukelyn Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/tbc.juke </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Future Projects Link to heading Create a Discord bot (again&amp;hellip;) Building small games to brush up on my programming skills Learning new programming languages. Somewhat interested in C++ and C&amp;hellip; Everything I do will from now on be documented on my site here and I am also considering the possibility of uploading my code to Github publicly so that others can actually have access to things I make!&#xA;Current Link to heading Currently I am trying to learn C when I have the time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
