<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webserver on Jukelyn</title>
    <link>http://jukelyn.com/categories/webserver/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webserver on Jukelyn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jukelyn.com/categories/webserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SSL/TLS Chain of Trust</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/tls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/tls/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is TLS/SSL? Link to heading TLS (Transport Layer Security) and SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) are cryptographic protocols designed to provide secure communication over a network. TLS was developed by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) in 1999 to be an upgrade/replacement for SSL which is was developed by Netscape in 1994.&#xA;Why should anybody care? Link to heading Now that you know what TLS and SSL are, why should we care?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup Nginx As A Webserver Using Portainer (Docker)</title>
      <link>http://jukelyn.com/posts/nginx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://jukelyn.com/posts/nginx/</guid>
      <description>Jump to Updates&#xA;What is nginx? Link to heading Nginx (pronounced &amp;ldquo;engine X&amp;rdquo;) is an open-source web server software known for its high performance, stability, and low resource usage. It serves static content, acts as a reverse proxy and load balancer, and can cache HTTP responses to improve speed and efficiency. Its simple configuration and ability to handle many simultaneous connections make it ideal for high-traffic websites. Nginx is widely used due to its flexibility and robust feature set, with both open-source and enterprise versions available.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
